（ノノハ）カイト！
（ギャモン）やべえ　ひとまず逃げるぞ。
Kaito!
Damn, we've gotta get outta here!
カイト！　逃げて！
Kaito! Run!
（ホイスト）これは…。
This...
（フリーセル）はははっ…　カイト。
Kaito...
ダブルリングに飲まれて暴走するとは…。
He was overwhelmed by the two rings and went berserk...
（フリーセル）行かなくちゃ。
うっ…　フリーセル様。
I must go.
Sir Freecell!
カイト…　君を死なせはしない。
Kaito, I can't let you die.
僕との約束を果たすまで…。
Not until you fulfill your promise to me.
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
Awakening
チェスト～！
Chesto!
あっ。　キューちゃん。
Cubie!
（キュービック）ノ　ノノハ…。
大丈夫？
Nonoha?
Are you okay?
うん…　なんとかね…。
I think...
あっ。　あれは…。
That's...
居た！
あっ。
ギャモンとアナだ。
There!
It's Gammon and Ana!
２人は無事だ。　でも　周りを
塞がれて身動きが取れないみたい。
They seem to be all right,
but they're locked in, so they can't move.
カイトは？
それが…　どこにも…。
And Kaito?
I don't see him anywhere.
あっ！
見つけた！　カイトだ！
There! It's Kaito!
やっぱり　あの崩壊で
一番下の階層まで落ちたんだ。
He really fell to the bottom level among the destruction.
Is Kaito all right?
カイトは無事なの？
脳波から見て
気を失ってるみたい。
Judging from his brainwaves, he's unconscious.
早く助けに行かなくちゃ。
無理だよ。
We have to help him!
We can't!
崩れた落下物が　カイトの真上に
積み重なってる。
The rubble is piled on top of him.
それに　ヨシオ君じゃあ
この落下物を取り除けないよ。
Yoshio can't clear through that.
そんな…。　どうにかして
カイトの所に行く方法はないの？
But... Isn't there some way to get down to him?
ちょっと待って。
One second...
これは…。
何　これ？
分からない。
This...
What's that?
I don't know, but it seems to be connected to where Kaito is.
でも　この構造物　カイトのいる階層と
つながってるみたい。
これを伝って行けば
カイトの所へ行けるかも。
We might be able to reach him that way.
はぁ…　行かなくちゃ。
私　カイトを助けに行ってくる。
I'll go.
I'm going to save Kaito!
あいつ１人なら　なんとか
担いで帰ってこられるし。
I can carry him back on my shoulder.
待って！　僕も行く！
Wait! I'm going too!
キューちゃんは　アナとギャモン君を
助けてあげて。
You should stay and help Gammon and Ana.
２人を助けるには
ヨシオ君の力が必要でしょう？
You need Yoshio to dig them out, right?
でも…。
But...
大丈夫。　キューちゃんが調べてくれた
地図は　全部　頭に入ってるから。
It's okay.
I memorized the map you showed me.
私の記憶力と　腕力を信じて。
分かった。
Believe in my strength and memory.
Okay.
カイトのこと　頼んだよ。
ガッテン！
I'm leaving Kaito to you!
Roger that!
Take care, Nonoha...
気をつけて　ノノハ。　僕たちは
ギャモンとアナを助けよう。
We should help Gammon and Ana.
…って　これって　まさか！？
Wait, no way!
パ・ズ・ルだぁ～。
It's a puzzle...
はぁ～　どうしよう？
What should I do?
これを伝って　降りろって言うの？
Are you telling me I'm supposed to get down with this?
頑張れ　井藤ノノハ。
You can do it, Itou Nonoha!
カイトを助けられるのは
私しか　居ないんだから。
You're the only one who can save Kaito!
カ　カイト！　今　行くわよ。
Kaito, I'm coming!
（フリーセル）無理だよ　君には。
あっ　あんたは！？
You can't do it.
You!
カイトは生きてるんだね。
Kaito is alive, right?
待ってて　カイト。
今　助けに行くから。
Wait for me, Kaito. I'm coming to save you.
カイトを助けに？　笑わせないでよ。
You're going to save Kaito?
Don't make me laugh.
カイトを危ない目にあわせてきた
あんたが？
All you've ever done for Kaito is put him in danger.
崩壊の衝撃で　空間そのものが
もろくなってるんだ。
Due to the shock of the destruction, this whole space is unstable.
巨大な組み木パズルか。　ムダなもの
ばかり作るね　ヘルベルトは。
A huge wooden puzzle? You only make useless stuff, Herbert.
まっ…　おかげで　カイトの所に
行けるんだけど。
I can get to Kaito with this, but...
全体の構造が見えない以上
なかなか難解だよ。
I don't know how it looks, so it's difficult to solve.
パズルの構造なら　分かるわ。
キューちゃんが調べたもの。
I know how this puzzle is constructed.
Cubie showed me that along with Kaito's position.
このパズルのことも　カイトの位置も
全部　頭に入ってる。
It's all in my head.
Really...
あんたのことは信じられない。
I can't trust you.
でも　もし本当に
カイトを助けてくれるなら…。
But if you'll really help Kaito...
うっ…。
ママの形見だ。
This is a memento of Mama.
僕にとって　カイトとの約束と
同じくらい　大事なものだ。
It's about as dear to me as my promise with Kaito.
これで　信じてくれるかい？
Will you trust me now?
分かった。
Fine.
あのパズルに挑戦するのですか？
Are you going to challenge that puzzle?
いいデータが取れることを
期待していますよ。
I'm expecting to collect some very good data.
始めようか。
今　僕たちが立っているブロック→
Let's start then.
Do you know where the block we're standing on connects?
どこと　つながっているか
分かるかい？
えっ！？
えっと～　たぶん…　あれ…。
Um... Probably that.
そう。
All right.
Amazing!
す　すごい…。
あれは？
えっ！？　あっ　ああ…　えっと…。
And that?
Um...
うっ。
よっと。
心の声
すごい…　こんなに簡単に…。
Amazing... He's doing it so easily.
ねえ。
ん？
Hey! Do you really want to help Kaito?
本当に　カイトを
助けようとしてるの？
もちろん。　カイトは死なせない。
Of course.
I can't let Kaito die until he's fulfilled his promise to me.
僕との約束を果たすまで…。
ピノクル君が言ってた。
Pinochle said that he didn't know how
あんたのママが死んだことと
カイトが約束を破ったことに→
your mother's death and Kaito's broken promise are connected.
どんな関係があるのか
分からないって。
カイトは　ずっと知りたがってる。
自分が何をしたのか。
Kaito is trying to remember what he did!
カイトは　あんたのことを
思い出したいから→
He came here because he wants to know more about you!
ここに来たのよ。
（足音）
お願い。　本当のことを教えて！
Please, tell me the truth!
カイトは　本当に　あんたのママを…。
Did Kaito really kill your mother?
勘違いしないでほしいな。
Please don't get me wrong.
僕と君は　カイトを助けるために
協力してるだけ。
You and I are only cooperating to save Kaito.
仲間でもない君に
話すことなんてないよ。
You're not my friend, so why would I tell you?
それは…　分かってるけど…。
I know that, but still...
まあ　いっか。
Fine then...
カイトはね　ママの思いと…
僕との約束を踏みにじったんだ。
Kaito...
stomped on the feelings of Mama and his promise with me.
僕はね　ずっと　カイトに
憧れていたんだ。
I've always adored Kaito.
どんなパズルにも　ひるまず
立ち向かい　解放してしまう…。
He'd challenge any puzzle without hesitation, and release it.
Th-The answers are all correct...
回想
（男子生徒）ぜ…　全問正解だ。
（フリーセル）そのひらめき　強さ　気高さ
全てが　まぶしかった。
His brightness, his strength, his willpower...
It was a blinding sight.
カイトと友達になれば
僕は変われるかもしれない…。
Maybe I would change if I became his friend.
彼なら　僕を
解放してくれるかもしれない。
Maybe he could release me.
そう思ったんだ。
That's what I thought.
解放って…　何から？
Release, but from what?
あっ…　まあ　いいや。
Whatever.
だから　うれしかったなぁ。
カイトと　パズルの約束ができた時は。
That's why I was happy when Kaito promised to puzzle with me.
えっ！？　パズルを一緒に？
回想
Play puzzles with you?
いいよ。　じゃあ　日曜日に。
回想
Sure!
On Sunday then!
（フリーセル）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
回想
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ。
ママ！　カイト君が　僕と
パズルしてくれるって！
Mama, I'm going to play puzzles with Kaito!
僕　約束したんだ。
回想
He promised!
（フリーセル）でも…。
But...
Kaito didn't come.
（フリーセル）カイトは来なかった。
彼は　僕との約束を破ったんだ…。
He broke his promise with me.
そして　その日
大好きなママは死んだ…。
And then, that day...
my beloved mother died.
僕が　カイトを待っている間に
ママは　急に容体が悪くなって…→
While I was waiting for Kaito,
Mama's condition suddenly worsened,
そのまま　息を引き取った。
and she died.
「病気の母親を置いて
遊びに出かけるとは→
People told me I was a cruel, evil child
なんて残酷で　親不幸な子供だ…」。
そう　言われたっけ。
for leaving my sick mother alone while I went out to play.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
ママが死んだのは…
カイトのせいじゃない。
Mama's death...
wasn't Kaito's fault...
NO SHIT
僕が　ママを死なせたんだ。
I let Mama die...
ちょ　ちょっと待って…。
Wait a minute...
ママはね　大したパズルも作れない
落ちこぼれの僕を嫌っていた。
Mama hated me for being a loser who couldn't make any decent puzzles.
そして　僕は→
And I...
そんなママを…　憎んでいた。
hated Mama for that too.
（フリーセル）この記憶は…　まがいもの。
These memories are all lies.
本物の記憶は　こっちだ。
The real ones are these.
思い出したよ…　全部ね。
I remember everything.
何　言ってるの！？
それが　本当のことだっていうの！？
What are you saying? Is that true?
何よ　それ。　訳　分かんない…。
What's this about? I don't get it!
じゃあ　今まで
カイトに言ってきたことは→
Then everything you said to Kaito isn't true?
全部　でたらめだったってこと！？
メチャクチャじゃないの　そんなの！
That's crazy!
あっ。
メチャクチャ？
Crazy? It might be.
かもね…。
But I didn't think so until just now.
でも　そうは思わなかったんだ。
つい　さっきまでは。
自分の記憶のことでしょう？
何　言って…　あっ！
But those are your own memories! What are you talk—
リングにゆがめられた
心の声
思いが　記憶を書き換える。
His feelings are warped by the ring and his memories are overwritten.
大好きなママは　大嫌い。
心の声
ママを死なせたのは　カイトじゃない。
He hated his mother, not loved her. It wasn't Kaito who made her die.
心の声
なのに　全部　カイトが悪いって…。
Yet, it's still all Kaito's fault...
何なのよ…　一体…。
What the heck does this mean?
あんたの言葉　一体　何が本物で
何が　でたらめなの？
Which parts are true and which are a lie?
もしかしたら　カイトと約束したって
いうのも　全部　でたらめなの？
Is the promise with Kaito a lie as well?
約束は…　本物だ。
The promise is real.
僕は　ずっと　あの約束だけを
支えに生きてきた。
That promise is what's kept me alive.
僕にとっては　神聖な約束。
僕にとっての全てなんだ。
It's sacred to me... It's everything to me!
その約束を冒とくするのなら
僕は君を許さない。
Disgrace that promise and you will pay dearly.
（ホイスト）記憶の改ざんの自己修正。
Automatic correction of the altered memories.
脳の感情領域のコントロール。
Control of the brain's emotional areas.
アップグレードにより
リングの安定性が増したようですね。
It would seem the ring's become much more stable with the upgrades.
ん？
（メランコリィ）あら　まだ居たの？　ホイ。
Ah, you're still here, Whi?
メランコリィ様。
まあ　珍しい組み合わせ。
Lady Melancholy.
What a rare combo.
２人で　仲よく　パズル中？
ええ。
The two of them have teamed up in a puzzle?
Yes. The numbers are amazing.
先ほどから　すばらしい数値です。
やはり　フリーセル様は
大門カイトが絡んだときにかぎり→
As long as Daimon Kaito is involved,
脳の強制活性化率が
跳ね上がるようで…。
the forced activation rate of Sir Freecell's brain is skyrocketing.
（ホイスト）やはり　フリーセル様を
スカウトして頂いて　正解でしたね。
You did the greatest job scouting him.
（フリーセル）えっ！？　転校？
回想
He transferred?
Didn't you hear? He went back to Japan.
回想
（級友）
知らないの？　日本に帰ったよ。
回想
これからは　ルート学園に
通うんだってさ。
He'll be attending the Root Academy from now on.
そうだったんだ…。
回想
I see...
行っちゃったんだ…　カイト君…。
You left... Kaito...
回想
結局　あの日から
一度も話せなかった。
We haven't spoken since that day.
回想
（メランコリィ）ひどいですわね　大門カイト。
あっ。
Isn't Daimon Kaito cruel...
回想
あなたとの約束
果たさずに逃げるなんて。
for running away without fulfilling his promise to you?
回想
ああっ　あの…　君たちは…。
Um... Who are you guys?
オルペウス・オーダー。
回想
The Orpheus Order.
フリーセルをスカウトしたことが正解？
Scouting Freecell was the greatest?
本当に　そうだといいけど。
Let's hope you're right.
W-What's happening?
なっ　何？
崩壊が始まった。　急ぐよ。
It's starting to collapse. Let's hurry.
このブロックは　どこのブロックと
つながってるの？
Where is this block connected?
えっと～。
遅い。
Um...
You're slow!
見えた。
I see it!
行かなくちゃ。　カイトのもとへ。
I must go to Kaito!
まっ　待って！　うっ。
Wait!
こ　これは…。
This...
ちょ　ちょっと待って。
どうなってるの？
Wait, what's going on?
私　さっきから　パズルのこと
何も教えてないのに。
I haven't said anything about the puzzle for a while now!
ふ～ん…　もう　パズルの全ては
把握しちゃったってわけね。
Oh? He's grasped the whole of the puzzle.
バカな。　脳の強制活性化率
計測不能だと！？
Impossible! His brain's forced activation rate is unmeasurable?!
この反応は　まるで！
This signal looks exactly...
（メランコリィ）あっ。
（ホイスト）何！？
What?
どうしたの？
What happened?
The data transfer from the ring stopped.
リングからのデータ転送が
停止しました。
（ホイスト）なぜ　こちらのコントロールを
受け付けない！？
Why won't it accept my orders?
ふ～ん…　これって…。
Ah, I see.
えいっ。
心の声
カイト　今　やっと気づいたよ。
Kaito, I've finally realized.
僕たちには
心の声
偽りの理由も　過去も　ママも→
We needed no false reasons...
No past, no Mama... None of those.
心の声
何にも必要なかったんだって。
I can... I can see...
見える…　見えるよ。
心の声
僕たちの…。
Our...
未来が…。
心の声
...future.
ギャモン！　アナ！　大丈夫？
Gammon! Ana!
Are you okay?
ああ　何とかな。　キュー太郎。
Yeah, not bad, Cuboy.
（アナ）助かったぞ　シオシオ！
Thank you, Shiyoshio!
カイトとノノハは　どうした？
What about Kaito and Nonoha?
（キュービック）詳しいことは　あと！
こっち　こっち。
That'll have to wait! This way!
こっちだ。
あっ…。
Follow me.
Kaito!
（２人）カイト！
フリーセル！　何で　てめえが　ここに。
Freecell! Why are you here?!
彼が…　フリーセル君が
助けてくれたの。　カイトを。
He... Freecell saved Kaito.
僕を信じてくれてありがとう。
井藤ノノハさん。
Thanks for trusting me, Itou Nonoha.
あの…　これ。
Here.
This is yours.
もう要らないんだ　それ。
えっ！？
I don't need it anymore.
僕にはもう　約束も　ママも
どうだっていいのさ。
The promise and Mama don't matter to me anymore.
だって…　分かっちゃったからね…
いろんなことが…。
You know,
I've figured out a bunch of things.
（フリーセル　モニター音）
「見てるんだろう？　ホイスト？」。
You're watching, aren't you, Whist?
（フリーセル）
この出来損ないの　まがいもの…→
I turned this incomplete, faulty piece of junk into the real thing.
本物にしちゃったよ。
あっ。
（フリーセル）「計画　台無しにしちゃって
ごめんね」。
Sorry for ruining your beautiful little plan.
あのリングが　本物…。
That ring is real?
どういうことだ？
（一同）あっ。
What's going on?
カイト！
Kaito!
大丈夫？　カイト！
Are you okay, Kaito?
フフッ。　カイト
君は僕を救いたいんだよね。
Kaito, you want to save me, right?
僕とのゲームに勝てば　このリングを
外すことができるよ。
If you can win a game against me, this ring will fall off.
でも　今の君では　僕に勝てない。
だって　僕は…。
But as you are now, you can't win against me.
Because now I'm...
もっと　もっと強くなってよ　カイト。
Keep getting stronger, Kaito!
そしたら　始めよう。
僕たちのパズルタイムを。
Then we can have our puzzle time.
フリー…　セル。
Freecell...
カイト！
（ギャモン）おい　しっかりしろ！
Kaito!
Hey, get a hold of yourself!
（キュービック）カイト！
（アナ）カイト！
Kaito!
しっかりして　カイト！　カイト～！
Wake up, Kaito!
Kaito!
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt